Any of you that have watched my videos
before would know that I don't like sales
calls. I don't. I've never done one.
I've made millions of dollars over several
businesses, never had to call someone
up, "Hey,
please can I have your money?" It's
because I'm lazy, and it's because I
hate phone calls. Even now, nothing
is better than me coming to a room on
my own, hitting record on a camera,
and not having to interact with other
human
beings. Love it. Absolutely love it.
I don't want to talk to people that much.
I don't want to interact with them,
don't want to give them my energy.
And if someone was to not show up to a
call, I'd be livid.
However,
even though I hate sales calls
and still believe that the majority of you
should have high-converting landing pages
and you should have a personal brand and
people trust you and all of that,
I'm willing to meet you in a middle
ground, and
I've called it and coined it the reverse
sales call.
Now,
there's going to be two different groups
of you.
You can have the B2B, the B2C. Now,
if you're in the B2B area or even the
B2C, business to business,
business to consumer,
you will have to be at some form
of established authority.
You would probably need a relative size
following,
maybe five to 10,000 above,
a decent email list,
and some kind of demand for your
services.
If you've just qualified as a PT
or a physio, probably not
the right strategy for you,
but still listen.
Now, if you're a B2B,
I'm actually going to test this over the
next few months.
I would need your name, email address,
socials, email size,
monthly recurring revenue. Now,
we will use the example of a PT,
I'm afraid.
Name, goal,
things they've struggled with before.
I'd actually probably say social media
and just an idea of what they've tried,
what
they've been frustrated by, et cetera.
But we're not going to use
that to flip against them.
We're not going to use that to trick them.
We're not going to use
that in some sales spiel on a call.
What we're going to do is this.
You're going to look through your list of
people
that you've got,
maybe by putting a wait list on,
maybe by marking that you're
closed, maybe by saying, "Hey,
I'm doing this in a few weeks' time.
What I need you to do is sign up
and just give me these bits of
information."
Because some people register their
interest, and these
are going to be people that
probably wouldn't have jumped on a sales
call with you.
All the people that want to do business
with you probably already have or will and
won't need this.
But some people just need a bit of
reassurance.
So what you're going to do,
they're not going to expect this.
You're not going to tell them this
is happening.
But you are going to record a five-minute
video, whether you use Loom or Tella or
whatever software you prefer,
and you're just going to look at your
prospect, and
you're going to send them a five-minute
video.
And in that video, just tell them
if they were to join the program,
what it might
look like. That's it.
I'll make one up off the top of my head.
I'll probably say, "Hi, John,
I saw your name come through.
I appreciate that we
are closed right now and
that we're not taking on new clients,
but I had a look at your profile.
I actually think you'd be a great fit.
Now, these are some of the problems
that I saw.
These are some of the things
that I'd like to work with you through.
And by the way, watching this video,
there's absolutely no pressure to work
with
me. I had five minutes between calls.
Thought I was going to pick a few names
and just give some free advice." Now, the
whole idea of this is actually,
I don't want you to think of it as a sales
call.
I want you to think of it as a five-minute
window to give a stranger free advice
that they could implement
and actually see a positive return whether
they join or
not. At the end of that, you'd go, "Hey,
that's just a taste of what it could be
like working with me.
I will also put a link to join in the
program below." You
could do three of those a day,
take 15 minutes,
and you would be able to get people
to charge full price for whatever it
is you're charging without a discount or
whatever it is because you would just make
them feel a little bit special for five
minutes. You can do it in your own time,
whenever you want.
You can start and stop again because
if some of you are low confidence,
you might
fumble a sentence
and then want to start the sentence again.
On a live call, you might be like, "Uh,
uh," it's a bit weird talking to a
stranger when you're trying to get them to
buy from you at the end.
Also,
this is just a good way for you to get
repetitions in or
potentially down the line critiquing
people's content, critiquing people's
workouts, critiquing people's diets,
whatever it is,
and genuinely helping people.
Because everything you should do in the
top level of your social media is to talk
and address the issues
that your clients have and face
and help them with it.
I'm asking you to do that again,
but more on a one-to-one basis.
I'm almost asking you to pick people from
your list to give one-to-one advice.
Now,
this is probably going to work better for
high ticket, and I've actually done
this before.
I put out an offer for $10,000.
I had to make it $12,500, and it
was me working with the person one-to-one.
I had to take it offline in two days
because too many people bought it.
I only just finished up the sessions with
people recently.
And one guy messaged me,
and his name's Jamie,
and he's an accountant, and I
thought straight away, "Oh my God,
I'm a bit overwhelmed.
I've never worked with an accountancy firm
before. What could I do?
How do I answer his email?" I recorded a
five-minute video going, "Hey, mate,
you've not posted enough content.
That's a start.
The money you pay me could be worth it in
me just getting you to post a few hundred
more times. These
are some of the issues I'm seeing with it.
You're putting text on a screen
and expecting people to read it.
You're putting too much in the caption.
I've been to your website.
It looks like this is the direction
that you want to move.
I would love to know a little bit more
about your clients, but either way, these
are probably the things
that I would focus on." Email came back.
Great. Let's go.
That to me, I just think
is a better use of time because
if you're on a call with
someone, it could end up going 45 minutes,
they still say no.
You get to control the time.
You get to control the narrative.
You get to control when, how,
and why you do it. Also,
there's no expectations.
You could look at your recurring revenue
for the month, go, "Oh, we're a little bit
light this month.
I'm going to send 10 out." Alternatively,
when you're busy and
the business is cranking
and YouTube videos
are really doing what they need to do,
you might go,
"I'm not doing any of these today." It's
on your terms.
It's not looking at your diary next week
and going, "Oh, I've got these calls.
I've got to move this." Because another
thing for me is my day's a bit chaotic.
On the drive here, I got distracted
and ended up going to do a blood test
because
I'm on tour with Chris next week.
I've got one call in my diary today at
1:30,
and my whole day is pretty much written
off because I'm so paranoid about
forgetting that one call. Now,
it turns out that call is a very,
very important
call. But still, I'm so glad
that I can do things on my terms
when I want.
I was feeling rather caffeinated this
morning from two cans of tonic and
two coffees, and I was like,
"I'm going to go film content." I'm not
controlled by
anything in my diary, really.
Apart from Thursdays. They suck.
I put everything bad on a Thursday.
And for a lot of you,
this could just give you the nudge you
need for your more
expensive product to just reach out to a
few people and go, "Hey, working with me
looks like this. These
are the problems I think you have.
This is how I'd solve it."
If this doesn't work, don't do it.
But for some of you, it could be
that perfect middle ground between having
to beg
people to buy your stuff on calls
and where you've maybe not attained the
skills of
email marketing or creating a nice-looking
landing page.
The reverse sales call could be your way
in. Something to think about.
And do you know what?
I actually got this idea from chatting to
someone in the
Discord this morning.
It's working with people
that I get ideas to teach
people. So imagine this.
I didn't just answer
that person's question in the
Discord. I did it on social media.
Because this way,
not only can the thousands of
people that work with me see it,
the thousands of people
that don't work with me
can see it.
Everything I teach as far as marketing,
getting sales online, is the
very thing I use for getting sales online.
So please do check out the links in the
description.
There's a segment of free stuff,
segment of paid stuff.
And I'll be honest with you, if you
were to buy from me and you
were to send me a
polite good email as to why you're
unhappy, I would of course make it right.
But if you message me going, "Hi, James.
Bought your thing nine months ago.
I've not used it. Can I get it back?" No.
No, you bloody can't.
I said go use it, you knob. Anyway,
hope you enjoyed that video.
If you don't want to do a reverse sales
call, check out this video here because
YouTube reckons it'll be a bloody banger,
mate.